# Josh Marquardt

Addison, TX 75001

(262) 455-1195

marquardt1195@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Software developer with 1 year of experience developing web applications in a fast-paced technology startup. Use C#, .NET, and SQL Server to build efficient back-end systems to work with dynamic front-end interfaces using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Able to communicate complex concepts in a simple and effective manner.

### **SKILLS**

- C#
- .NET
- Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- SQL (SQL Server, MySQL)

- Entity Framework
- API Development/Integration
- Git
- R (data analysis & visualization)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Junior Software Developer**

January 2024 - Present

Low Cost Pet Tech, Co.

- Developed RESTful APIs to consolidate a deprecated database into the new architecture, improving
  data integrity and enhanced coverage for over 150,000 customer accounts. Optimized system
  efficiency by offloading messaging tasks, achieving a 10% reduction in server load during peak hours.
- Integrated third-party APIs, including Google Maps, Radar, American Kennel Club (AKC Reunite), Homebase, and Kickbox, into new and existing software solutions.
- Enhanced software performance by using various data structures, including XML & JSON.
- Assisted in communicating key technical concepts and project plans to company executives.

## **Software Development Intern**

September 2023 – January 2024

Low Cost Pet Tech, Co.

 Created a company-wide inventory management system from the ground up, improving efficiency and accuracy in inventory tracking using C# with .NET, Entity Framework, and SQL Server.

### **Business Owner**

January 2021 – July 2023

SLC Vintage Goods LLC

- Co-founded online vintage furniture company with avg. of 93% YoY revenue growth since inception.
- Used HTML and CSS to develop company website: <u>slcvintagegoods.github.io</u>

## **Graduate Research Fellow**

August 2018 - December 2020

University of Utah & Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory

• Used R to analyze, process, and visualize data to conduct original research in geophysics. Published sample: Figure 3 in <a href="https://sd.copernicus.org/articles/25/35/2019/">https://sd.copernicus.org/articles/25/35/2019/</a>

### **EDUCATION**

University of Utah – M.S., Geophysics

August 2018 – December 2020

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee – B.S., Geosciences

January 2014 - May 2018